Bert JW Regeer

Bert JW Regeer Tel: +1-480-264-0039 Email: bertjw@regeer.org

Profile

I am a highly motivated individual, someone who enjoys exploring new technology and applying the knowledge gained in new and exciting ways. My strongest point is my knowledge of the UNIX/Linux system environment with strong administration skills as well as knowledge of the systems themselves. C++ and Python are currently the two programming languages I know best, like any good programmer I am easily able to master new programming languages. I've worked with customers on many different projects and helped solve difficult problems they were facing. Other interests include electronics (hardware engineering), embedded systems and network security. I am knowledgeable in writing secure software that doesn't contain common pitfalls that lead to vulnerable software.

Skills

Operating Systems	Software	Languages	Databases
Mac OS X	Version Control (git/hg/svn/cvs)	C++	PostgreSQL
FreeBSD	Bugtraq/JIRA/Github	C	MySQL
Linux	vim	Python	sqlite3
Microsoft Windows Server (2003/2008)	Gitorious	C#	
Microsoft Windows (2000/XP/Vista/7)	Visual Studio (2003/2005/2008/2010)	Java	
		JavaScript	

Experience

Owner and Founder, CEO; Colossal Dynamics Corporation - February 2011 - current

- » Founder and owner
- » Client/corporate relationship management
- » Embedded platform engineer
- » Product currently in development with availability to public in 2012
- » Founded in Colorado.

Application Systems Analyst/Programmer; iPhase3 Corporation - June 2010 - current

- » Designed and implemented the backend system for our first product
- » Using a mix of C++ and Python built services that communicate using ZeroMQ
- » Wrote and tested the services
- » Used PostgreSQL to provide an easy and fast way to store various bits of data
- » Architect the system for high availability with failover
- » Work with the stakeholders to produce the functionality required
- » Worked with various teams working on all the different moving parts in the system

System Administrator/Web Master; osnn.net - 2002 - current

- » Configure, maintain, secure and administrate FreeBSD and services
- » Tune server resources for the load
- » Migrating live website to new location
- » Monitoring of services for reliability and uptime (SSH, httpd, email)
- » Securing and threat assessment
- » Basic web-master duties/forum moderation

System Administrator; netuse.co.uk - August 2006 - current

- » Configure, maintain, secure and administrate FreeBSD and services
- » Monitoring of services for reliability and uptime (SSH, httpd, email)
- » Shell scripting to backup user data and e-mail
- » 24/7 stand-by, on-call administration
- » Using FreeBSD as a server platform has achieved greater uptime and availability

Owner and Founder, Developer; Colossal Dynamics Corporation - January 2009 - June 2011

- » Founder and part owner
- » Software developer for internal applications
- » Client/corporate relationship management
- » On-site work for clients
- » Embedded platform engineer
- » Founded in Arizona, dissolved in 2011

Website Engineer/Lead Designer (internship); AEC Consultants - 2009 - 2009

- » Design company website
- » Design and build Zend Framework based backend for dynamic content
- » Design and build MySQL based database as a backend
- » Train users to update content on the site and answer RFP's

Volunteer worker (temp); Blackhat - July 2008, 2009, 2010

- » Check people in and provide conference badges
- » Lay network and power cables for the students in the classes
- » Set up wireless nodes for Aruba networks
- » Sell T-Shirts and other Blackhat swag in the Black Hat store
- » Help people find their way around the conference
- » Stuff swag bags

Security Audit; University of Advancing Technology - February 2007 - April 2007

- » General network security audit
- » Finding exploits in intranet web applications (SQL Injections)
- » Pen testing
- » Analyses of network protocols

Projects

These are the projects I am currently involved in, or have been involved in.

Near Space

As a team of 15 students we developed a near space pay-load along with the various science experiments. With a GPS device TNC and a HAM radio on-board we were able to track the near space pay-load using APRS data that was being sent back. After retrieving the pay-load we were able to retrieve the science data along with the pictures that we had taken with a still camera.

Open Source

I am a big proponent and supporter of Open Source software, a lot of the software I've written is available for free from my <u>Github</u> page located at https://github.com/bertjwregeer/. This includes my most recent samples of code.

Education

2006 - 2009, University of Advancing Technology; Tempe, Arizona

Degree: Bachelor of Science: Software Engineering

Major: Computer Programming